LUKE HAMMOND

UX/UI DESIGNER | DIGITAL MARKETING | VIDEO EDITOR

Experience |

UX/UI Designer

Housing Matters | Oct 2023 - Present

In this project I and two others have to create an accessible, on-brand, intuitive user interface for prospective clients, funders, partners, and individual supporters using WordPress. This has to be search engine optimised as well as mobile responsive.

Copy & Content Creator PANDEK Group | Mar 2023 - Present

As a Copy and Content Creator my role requires content creation in the form of blogs, newsletters, websites as well as video/graphic pieces. In addition to this, my role involves SEO, pitching ideas as well as proofing work.

This is done in a team setting to create the best pieces of work on social platforms that will engage an audience and inform them of the business' vision.

Content Creator (SCC) UWE Bristol | Nov 2022 - Oct 2023

As a Content Creator for UWE, I would follow a brief I requested for or either proposed. In this role I gained many skills such as recording professionally and collaboratively, editing videos for numerous platforms as well as adaptability to any other issues that occurred.

Being a competitive environment with many others wanting a job I had to grow thick skin to deal with rejection from a role or having a proposal refused. However, this only made me strive for the next piece of work.

Skills & Ability

Well versed in using a multitude of Adobe products such as After Effects, Premiere Pro, Illustrator, InDesign & Acrobat.

Confident in using Figma effetively for prototyping and creating UI.

Report writing of different styles such as technical reports.

Capable of using MS Office with PowerPoints being used by clients and jobs.

Capable in coding languages such as HTML, CSS & JavaScript

About Me

I am a confident and team-oriented individual who has a passion for UX/UI, Video Design and Digital Marketing. Always pushing the boundaries of creativity and accessibility; I desire for my work to revolutionise the current design climate. Communal activities with friends and family keep me grounded and allow for a refreshing world view.

I have two years of experience with a lot of adobe software such as After Effects, Premiere Pro and Illustrator. I like pushing the limits in these appliances and striving for the best piece of work possible, what started as a hobby is now a great passion of mine and I love seeing the results and happiness created by these works.

In addition, I am proficient with Figma and Miro, great websites for UX design. My passion for UX comes from a place of convenience, I can empathize with users who struggle with appliances and therefore I want everything to be its simplest and most efficient form. This can be done for all audiences, and I am always eager to learn more from teachings or talking to a community to produce the best piece of work that I can.

Education

University of the West of England (UWE Bristol)

Sep 2021 - Jul 2024

Bachelor of Science in Digital Media which I am predicted a $2.1\,\mathrm{or}$ higher.

Studied UX/UI for three years with multiple presentations and involvement in group work.

Experience with real clientele and working to a brief.

Creating a recommendation documentation in the field of UX/UI for dissertation.

Researched and studied general digital design for three years in the form of graphic design, video editing, animation and more.

Lord Williams's Upper School, Thame Sep 2018 - May 2020

Awarded a B in Media Studies, and a C for Geography and Philosophy & Ethics respectively.

Learnt a lot about ethical codes as well as the weight of political views on subjects.

SOFT SKILLS

Problem Solving, Customer Service, Empathetic, Patient, Group Work, Competitive, Organisation, Time Management